SIMON DENNIS OKELLO

Tel: +254 702440280 or +254 751050995 Email: simonokello93@gmail.com

PROFILE SUMMARY

Motivated IT support technician seeks new position in dynamic, growth-oriented company focused on cultivating exceptional customer experience and a positive work environment. With experience handling networking concerns, implementing new software, installing new hardware, and addressing user concerns, I bring attention to detail and a dedication to technical improvement to each job.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Year of birth: 1993

EDUCATION

- Bsc. Business Information Technology- Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology: 2014 – 2018
- Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education (KCSE)- Butula Boys High School: 2010 -2013

KEY SKILLS

- User Support
- Customer Service
- Hardware and Software Maintenance
- Windows and Linux Operating Systems.
- Software Installations.
- Networking and Troubleshooting.
- Printer Installation and Configurations
- Web Development and Programming

WORK HISTORY

ICT Intern;

Pest Control Products Board; July 2019 to date Duties and Responsibilities

Pest Control Products Board is a statutory organization of Government that provides an efficient and effective regulatory service for importation, exportation, manufacture, distribution, transportation, sale, disposal and use of pest control products and mitigate potential harmful effects to the environment.

- Troubleshooting users' technical and operational problems.
- Termination of UTP cat5 cables using RJ 45 connectors.
- Configuring PCs to the network through the TCP/IP protocol.
- Troubleshooting network problems using 'ping' command.
- Installing network cards in Laser Printers and networked PCs.
- Sharing printers for use in the local network.
- Maintenance of input and output devices.
- Installation of operating systems.
- Installation of in-house softwares.

Data Clerk;

Cloud Factory Kenya; June 2018 to July 2019

Duties and Responsibilities

Cloud Factory is a cloud labor platform where businesses get instant access to virtual workers for tedious and repetitive tasks. They are masters of the art and science of labeling data for Machine Learning and more using virtually any tool on the plane

- Preparing source data for computer entry by compiling and sorting information; establishing entry priorities.
- Entry of client and account data by inputting alphabetic and numeric information on keyboard or optical scanner according to format.
- Handle client and account source record by reassessing data for imperfections; settling discrepancies by utilizing standard procedures.
- Confirm account and customer information that was entered and correct, evaluate, delete and re-entering information when it is incomplete or when clearing out files to get rid of duplication.
- Contribute to team effort by accomplishing related results as needed.
- Filling of indexed documents as indexed for easy retrieval.

ICT Intern;

Kenya Power and Lighting Company; September 2016 to November 2018. Duties and Responsibilities

Kenya Power and Lighting Company is a limited liability company that transmits, distributes and retails electricity to customers throughout Kenya.

- Troubleshooting users' technical and operational problems.
- Termination of UTP cat5 cables using RJ 45 connectors.
- Configuring PCs to the network through the TCP/IP protocol.
- Troubleshooting network problems using 'ping' command.
- Installing network cards in Laser Printers and networked PCs.
- Sharing printers for use in the local network.
- Maintenance of input and output devices.
- Installation of operating systems.
- Installation of in-house softwares.
- Installing and running anti-virus program.
- Changing the fuser unit and adjusting laser unit of Laser printers.
- HP 4050 and 4V, Epson cash receipting printers and desk jets.
- Installation of both local and network printers.

REFEREES

Silas Bett

IT Technician

Kenya Power and Lighting Company Ltd

Email: bertbec@gmail.com
Tel: +254 720179114

Jacqueline Karuiki

Project Lead

Cloudfactory Kenya

Email: <u>jacqueline@cloudfactory.com</u>

Tel: +254729212529

Jackson Makokha

Sales Consultant

Baobab Development Group

Email: jackmakokha254@gmail.com

Tel: 0714813521